<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mapping on OWASP SAMM</title><link>https://owaspsamm.org/categories/mapping/</link><description>Recent content in mapping on OWASP SAMM</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://owaspsamm.org/categories/mapping/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Enabling teams with the OWASP SAMM Skills Framework</title><link>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2025/02/09/owasp-samm-skills-framework/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2025/02/09/owasp-samm-skills-framework/</guid><description>Introduction Picture this: your team is tasked with building secure, compliant software, but you’re not sure where to begin and who to involve. In today’s cloud-driven world, even solid security plans can stall if teams don’t know what tasks they own or believe they do not have the right skills to get started. Across teams, many organizations lack a clear view on ownership and shared responsibilities, whether they work with company internal service providers or external public service providers.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft SDL and OWASP SAMM Mapping: A Comprehensive Analysis</title><link>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2025/01/20/comparing-microsoft-sdl-and-samm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2025/01/20/comparing-microsoft-sdl-and-samm/</guid><description>Microsoft SDL and OWASP SAMM Mapping: A Comprehensive Analysis Introduction The Microsoft Security Development Lifecycle (SDL) was introduced in 2004 as Microsoft’s response to the security challenges that plagued its Windows operating system. As the first formal secure SDLC framework, it laid the foundation for many secure software development practices.
Today in its latest version, Microsoft SDL comprises 10 security practices, each containing a set of requirements designed to reduce security risks across the software development lifecycle.</description></item><item><title>SAMM BSIMM Mapping</title><link>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2024/12/10/samm-bsimm-mapping/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2024/12/10/samm-bsimm-mapping/</guid><description>Building Security In Maturity Model (BSIMM) Mapped to OWASP SAMM The full mapping sheet between BSIMM 14 and OWASP SAMM. Introduction The Building Security In Maturity Model (BSIMM) and OWASP Software Assurance Maturity Model (SAMM) share a common history. Both were conceived around 2008-2009 and are based on OpenSAMM, which was created by Pravir Chandra. Over time, however, these two models have evolved independently, with distinct conceptual differences. We have previously explored these differences in detail .</description></item><item><title>Tackling App Security with SAMM-NIST SSDF Mapping</title><link>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2023/02/06/samm-ssdf-mapping/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2023/02/06/samm-ssdf-mapping/</guid><description>The Application Security Challenge The increasing dependence on software in our daily lives has made the challenge of ensuring its security more pressing. Despite being a critical concern, cybersecurity is often not a priority for organizations until there is an incident or breach. This has resulted in the cost of cyber insurance doubling in the past two years and the total cost of cybercrime in 2022 reaching $7 trillion .</description></item></channel></rss>