<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on OWASP SAMM</title><link>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on OWASP SAMM</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://owaspsamm.org/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Microsoft SDL and OWASP SAMM Mapping: A Comprehensive Analysis</title><link>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2025/01/20/comparing-microsoft-sdl-and-samm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2025/01/20/comparing-microsoft-sdl-and-samm/</guid><description>Microsoft SDL and OWASP SAMM Mapping: A Comprehensive Analysis Introduction The Microsoft Security Development Lifecycle (SDL) was introduced in 2004 as Microsoft’s response to the security challenges that plagued its Windows operating system. As the first formal secure SDLC framework, it laid the foundation for many secure software development practices.
Today in its latest version, Microsoft SDL comprises 10 security practices, each containing a set of requirements designed to reduce security risks across the software development lifecycle.</description></item><item><title>SAMM BSIMM Mapping</title><link>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2024/12/10/samm-bsimm-mapping/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2024/12/10/samm-bsimm-mapping/</guid><description>Building Security In Maturity Model (BSIMM) Mapped to OWASP SAMM The full mapping sheet between BSIMM 14 and OWASP SAMM. Introduction The Building Security In Maturity Model (BSIMM) and OWASP Software Assurance Maturity Model (SAMM) share a common history. Both were conceived around 2008-2009 and are based on OpenSAMM, which was created by Pravir Chandra. Over time, however, these two models have evolved independently, with distinct conceptual differences. We have previously explored these differences in detail .</description></item><item><title>OWASP SAMM now connects to OpenCRE</title><link>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2023/09/20/owasp-samm-now-connects-to-opencre/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2023/09/20/owasp-samm-now-connects-to-opencre/</guid><description>We are excited to announce that each OWASP-SAMM stream now uses OpenCRE.org to link to other standards and guidelines. OpenCRE stands for Open Common Requirement Enumeration, and it aims to provide a common language and framework for mapping and comparing different security standards, guidelines, and frameworks. By linking SAMM to OpenCRE, we’ve made it easier for our users to find relevant and useful resources with every stream, as well as to see how SAMM aligns with other security standards such as NIST SSDF, ISO27K, PCI-DSS, OWASP ASVS, and NIST 800-53.</description></item><item><title>Determining scope when implementing SAMM</title><link>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2023/05/24/determining-scope-when-implementing-samm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2023/05/24/determining-scope-when-implementing-samm/</guid><description>When performing a SAMM assessment, should the scope be the whole organization or should it be smaller, like a business unit or even a single team or application?
The short answer? Start small.
Getting started Start by evaluating your goals. What do you want to achieve?
Do you aim to identify and prioritize areas of improvement in your organization&amp;rsquo;s security posture? Do you seek to establish a baseline for measuring the effectiveness of your security program over time?</description></item><item><title>How ISO and SAMM complement each other</title><link>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2023/03/21/how-iso-and-samm-complement-each-other/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2023/03/21/how-iso-and-samm-complement-each-other/</guid><description>October 2022 brought us the third revision of the ISO/IEC 27001 standard.
The revisions included simplifying the domains and controls, using more practical language, and introducing new controls. The addition of a separate control for &amp;ldquo;Secure Coding.&amp;rdquo; provides an opportunity to highlight how OWASP SAMM and ISO 27001 are complementary standards.
In this blog post, we shine light on how they intersect and how, implemented together, you can maximize their effectiveness and value.</description></item><item><title>The "Not Applicable" Question</title><link>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2023/02/28/the-not-applicable-question/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2023/02/28/the-not-applicable-question/</guid><description>The Core Team&amp;rsquo;s Thoughts Since the initial publication of SAMM 2.0, several SAMM users have asked how to address Activities or Quality Criteria they believe are not applicable to their assessment’s scope. At the recent SAMM Core Team Summit in Boston, we discussed this question at some length, and this article summarizes that conversation. The topic really involves several questions, which we’ll address one at a time.
Is it valid to declare an Activity Not Applicable?</description></item><item><title>Tackling App Security with SAMM-NIST SSDF Mapping</title><link>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2023/02/06/samm-ssdf-mapping/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2023/02/06/samm-ssdf-mapping/</guid><description>The Application Security Challenge The increasing dependence on software in our daily lives has made the challenge of ensuring its security more pressing. Despite being a critical concern, cybersecurity is often not a priority for organizations until there is an incident or breach. This has resulted in the cost of cyber insurance doubling in the past two years and the total cost of cybercrime in 2022 reaching $7 trillion .</description></item><item><title>Introducing SAMM Practitioners</title><link>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2022/12/05/introducing-samm-practitioners/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2022/12/05/introducing-samm-practitioners/</guid><description>Why SAMM Practitioners? We want to adopt OWASP SAMM 2.0 at my workplace. Can you recommend a company to help us do this?
SAMM team members get asked this a lot through the different channels of communication like our Slack channel and the contact form on the website.
Obviously, we know many companies, organizations, and individuals who can do this. We are a community-driven project and a number of volunteers have contributed to SAMM so it wasn’t an easy answer for us to provide.</description></item><item><title>Addressing Log4J vulnerabilities with SAMM</title><link>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2022/02/07/addressing-log4j-vulnerabilities-with-samm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2022/02/07/addressing-log4j-vulnerabilities-with-samm/</guid><description>It’s that dreaded notification. The one that holds the threat, and later the reality, of many sleepless nights. The newest vulnerability is here and its severity is considered critical.
This Log4J vulnerability (CVE-2021-44228) has caused quite the stir, and rightfully so. It’s kept security peeps on our toes for the last few months so it was interesting to see this topic come up during our last SAMM monthly community call.</description></item><item><title>OWASP SAMM Train the Trainer</title><link>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2021/11/30/owasp-samm-train-the-trainer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2021/11/30/owasp-samm-train-the-trainer/</guid><description>Expanding awareness of OWASP SAMM To introduce new users to the OWASP Software Assurance Maturity Model (SAMM), the SAMM project team has presented their one-day overview training class several times each year. These classes often run in conjunction with OWASP&amp;rsquo;s global and regional conference events. The instructors for that training class - currently titled &amp;ldquo;Secure Your SDLC using OWASP SAMM - ASAP!&amp;rdquo; - have usually been the project&amp;rsquo;s leaders, Sebastien (Seba) Deleersnyder and Bart de Win, or other SAMM team members.</description></item><item><title>Towards a well-governed SAMM Suite</title><link>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2021/03/23/samm-suite/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2021/03/23/samm-suite/</guid><description>Improving the velocity of OWASP SAMM Some years back, SAMM was a typical old school documentation project. Creation of all the documents was a purely manual and error-prone process. We fought a very complicated manual build procedure of the project PDF which only a few people knew how to deal with. Already fixed errors kept reappearing and it was hard to know who actually had the latest version in their mailbox.</description></item><item><title>OWASP SAMM Roadmap</title><link>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2021/02/09/owasp-samm-roadmap/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2021/02/09/owasp-samm-roadmap/</guid><description>What happened in 2020? This was a special year but still a lot happened for SAMM. The team worked hard to continue delivering and adding value for our users.
New version, new website, new ways of getting together In 2020 we launched OWASP SAMM v2.0, more than 10 years after OpenSAMM v1.0 was launched on March 25th, 2009 by Pravir Chandra.
Throughout 2020 we developed and released a new website and promoted the launch of SAMM v2.</description></item><item><title>Comparing BSIMM &amp; SAMM</title><link>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2020/10/29/comparing-bsimm-and-samm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2020/10/29/comparing-bsimm-and-samm/</guid><description>Building Security In Maturity Model (BSIMM) compared to Software Assurance Maturity Model (SAMM) A common origin BSIMM (Building Security In Maturity Model) and SAMM (Software Assurance Maturity Model) have similar origins dating back to a common origin back in 2008-2009. I’m frequently asked about what is similar and what is different between the two models, so I wrote up this comparison to help organizations understand which of these two models may be a better fit for their needs.</description></item><item><title>SAMM is doing CI/CD</title><link>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2020/03/31/samm-is-doing-cicd/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2020/03/31/samm-is-doing-cicd/</guid><description>What version 2 brought along A significant change that happened behind the scenes for SAMM 2.0 was the addition of a CI/CD pipeline, the automated version of all the steps we need to deliver SAMM. It has enhanced our productivity, providing standardization and enabling faster iterations. At the core of Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery are speed of delivery, reliability, and visibility. This process encourages frequent updates, allows quick fixes, and ensures a set of checks before deployment.</description></item><item><title>OWASP SAMM version 2 - public release</title><link>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2020/01/31/samm2-release/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2020/01/31/samm2-release/</guid><description>After three years of preparation, our SAMM project team has delivered version 2 of SAMM! OWASP SAMM (Software Assurance Maturity Model) is the OWASP framework to help organizations assess, formulate, and implement, through our self-assessment model, a strategy for software security they can integrate into their existing Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC).
The new SAMM v2 consists of the following components:
The SAMM Model overview and introduction, explaining the maturity model in detail A Quick-start Guide with different steps to improve your secure software practice An updated SAMM Toolbox to perform SAMM assessments and create SAMM roadmaps A new SAMM Benchmark initiative to compare your maturity and progress with other similar organizations and teams What&amp;rsquo;s changed with SAMM v2?</description></item><item><title>SAMM V2 community release</title><link>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2019/12/20/version2-community-release/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2019/12/20/version2-community-release/</guid><description>SAMM v2 community launch! After three years of preparation, our SAMM project team has delivered release 2 of SAMM!
First, we&amp;rsquo;re releasing SAMM v2 to the OWASP community and then plan our public release for mid-January 2020. We value your feedback and questions. To contribute, do one of the following, in decreasing order of preference:
add issues to our SAMM Github repository Complete the Google form per issue Start a discussion on our #project-samm Slack channel on OWASP.</description></item><item><title>Open Security Summit 2019</title><link>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2019/07/10/open-security-summit-2019/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 13:07:31 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2019/07/10/open-security-summit-2019/</guid><description>SAMM track, an overview and commentary of the event The Open Security Summit 2019 focused on the collaboration between Developers and Application Security and was organised with the support of OWASP. The 5-day sprint on SAMMv2 enabled attendees to work and collaborate intensively towards specific Application Security challenges with a focus on actionable outcomes. In addition to specific Maturity Models sessions, a large number of OWASP SAMM Working Sessions took place at the Summit.</description></item><item><title>Version 2 Beta</title><link>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2019/02/02/version2-beta/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 21:49:20 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/2019/02/02/version2-beta/</guid><description>The original model (v1.0) was written by Pravir Chandra and dates back from 2009. Over the last 10 years, it has proven a widely distributed and effective model for improving secure software practices in different types of organisations throughout the world. Translations and supporting tools have been contributed by the community to facilitate adoption and alignment. With version 2.0, we further improve the model to deal with some of its current limitations.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/1/01/01/samm-relative-scoring/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://owaspsamm.org/blog/1/01/01/samm-relative-scoring/</guid><description>SAMM Scoring and Percentage to Target Metric Introduction: the “not applicable” answer A common question among SAMM users is whether specific activities, streams, or entire practices can be marked as not applicable. This seems reasonable—some security activities might not fit an organization’s current reality. For example, the Supplier Security stream focuses on supply-chain risks in outsourced development. If your organization doesn’t outsource, it might seem irrelevant. The SAMM core team acknowledges this, but emphasizes future readiness.</description></item></channel></rss>