<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>model on OWASP SAMM</title><link>https://owaspsamm.org/resource_tags/model/</link><description>Recent content in model on OWASP SAMM</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://owaspsamm.org/resource_tags/model/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SAMM assessment tools</title><link>https://owaspsamm.org/resources/assessment-tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://owaspsamm.org/resources/assessment-tools/</guid><description>Links to info and tools If you want to learn more about SAMM assessments, we have a dedicated assessment page for that. If you&amp;rsquo;re just looking for the links to our spreadsheets or online assessment, here they are.
Spreadsheets We have 2 versions of the SAMM Toolbox, a Microsoft Excel Toolbox and a Google Spreadsheet Toolbox .
Online assessment SAMMwise is part of the official SAMM toolset and allows you to self-host an online assessment tool.</description></item><item><title>Training</title><link>https://owaspsamm.org/resources/training/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://owaspsamm.org/resources/training/</guid><description>A fully free, self-paced course with over 5 hours of video content.
Visit the SAMM Fundamentals Course page on Thinkific.
We&amp;rsquo;d really appreciate feedback on this first version of the course. Please use our Slack channel , the Discussions on GitHub or our contact form.</description></item><item><title>SAMM PDF</title><link>https://owaspsamm.org/resources/pdf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://owaspsamm.org/resources/pdf/</guid><description>This is a long awaited moment since the release of SAMM version 2. The community asked for it so we&amp;rsquo;ve created a PDF version of the model.
View the SAMM PDF here .
If you have any feedback on this, please use our Slack channel , the Discussions on GitHub or our contact form.</description></item><item><title>SAMM GitHub repositories</title><link>https://owaspsamm.org/resources/github/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://owaspsamm.org/resources/github/</guid><description>One project, many repos After the release of SAMM v2, we moved all of our GitHub content to the OWASP SAMM GitHub organization . Here, you can find all the repositories related to the SAMM project.
Some of the repos you can find there are:
Core Model Website SAMMwise (assessment tool) Also, don&amp;rsquo;t miss the Discussions section, where you can pitch your ideas, ask questions, and provide feedback.</description></item></channel></rss>